<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright 2002-2004 The Apache Software Foundation or its licensors,
  as applicable.

  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at

      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE faqs PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD FAQ V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/faq-v20.dtd">

<faqs>
  <title>Project FAQ</title>
    <faq>
      <question>
	    When did the Celtix project begin?
      </question>
      <answer>
      The Celtix project was formed in June 2005 and the first code was placed in the forge in 
	  July 2005. Since starting, the Celtix project has achieved five consecutive on-schedule 
	  milestone deliveries. In May of 2006, the Celtix project released its 1.0 build.
      </answer>
    </faq>
		<faq>
	<question>
	What is the road map for Celtix?
	</question>
	<answer>
	As with all open source project road maps, the road map for Celtix is dependent on the 
	needs of the users and the willingness of contributors to work on those features. There 
	is a list of proposed features on the mile stone page at 
	https://wiki.objectweb.org/celtix/Wiki.jsp?page=Milestones. We welcome user feedback 
	on the developer mailing list.
	</answer>
	</faq>
	<faq>
	<question>
	How do I contribute to the Celtix project?
	</question>
	<answer>
	Celtix is an open source project and accepts all contributions that are approved by the 
	community. To find out more about contributing, visit the Celtix project's getting started 
	page at https://wiki.objectweb.org/celtix/Wiki.jsp?page=GettingStarted.
	</answer>
	</faq>
	<faq>
	<question>
    Are there any licensing restrictions that apply to using Celtix?
	</question>
	<answer>
    Celtix is licensed under both the LPGL and the EPL. The packages for distribution under each 
	license is available from the download page. For more information, see the <a href="site:license">License FAQ</a>.
	</answer>
	</faq>
		<faq>
	<question>
	What is a milestone release?
	</question>
	<answer>
	<p>A milestone release is an interim release of Celtix that occurs at regular intervals so that users can 
	take advantage of new features without having to build Celtix from the repository. Each milestone release 
	contains new features and functionality (sometimes, partly implemented), but there is no guarantee that 
	testing is complete. In general, milestone releases should be regarded as less stable and are not 
	suitable for deployment.</p>
    <p>This contrasts with regular releases of Celtix, where every effort is made to ensure that the release 
	is stable and testing is complete.</p>
	</answer>
	</faq>
</faqs>
