<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document> 
  <header> 
    <title>CeltiXfire Demos</title> 
	<abstract>This page is a collection of samples showing what people have developed for CeltiXfire or on top of CeltiXfire. The intent is to demonstrate CeltiXfire's capabilities and provide a starting point for developers.</abstract>
  </header> 
  <body> 
    <section>
      <title>Overviews</title>
    <table>
        <tr>
          <td>
            <a href="#intalio">
              Intalio Integration
            </a>
          </td>
          <td>
            This demo describes how to write two CeltiXfire applications:
            <ul>
              <li>an application that kicks off an Intalio|n3 process</li>
              <li>an application that provides the business logic representing an Intalio|n3 task.</li>
            </ul>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>
            <a href="#rss">
              RSS Integration
            </a>
          </td>
          <td>
            This demo shows how to use RSS as a place to syndicate Web services in a simple way using CeltiXfire and RSSLib4J.
            It shows how to wrap the RSSLib4J APIs in order to use them to implement a name lookup for a WSDL from a RSS feed.
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>
            <a href="#bpel">
              ActiveBPEL Integration
            </a>
          </td>
          <td>
            This demo shows how to use the ActiveBPEL business process engine to
            coordinate information flow between multiple CeltiXfire Web services. This demo also shows interoperability between
            CeltiXfire and the ActiveBPEL engine, which uses Axis as its underlying Web services toolkit.
          </td>
        </tr>
    </table>
	</section>
    <section>
      <title>Detailed Descriptions</title>
	  <section id="intallio">
		<title>Intalio Integration</title>
		<p><strong>Description:</strong>
      An Intalio|n3 business process may be exposed as a Web service, which allows a client application to
      initiate a business process by sending a Web service request. Additionally, a task within an Intalio|n3
      business process may represent an invocation on a distributed Web service. When the process reaches
      this task, Intalio|n3 sends a Web services request to the external Web service. This application note
      describes how to write two CeltiXfire applications:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>An application that kicks off an Intalio|n3 process</li>
        <li>An application that provides the business logic representing an Intalio|n3 task</li>
      </ul>
    <p><strong>Contributed by:</strong> John Lifter</p>
    <p><strong>Created:</strong> 29 December 2005</p>
    <p><strong>Last updated:</strong> 29 December 2005</p>
    <p><strong>Tested with:</strong> Celtix 1.0</p>
    <p><strong>Download:</strong></p>
    <ul>
      <li>Overview (<a href="./intalio/celtix_intalio_integration.pdf">pdf</a>)</li>
      <li>Source (<a href="./intalio/celtix_intalio_integration.zip">zip</a>)</li>
    </ul>
	  </section>
	  <section id="rss">
		<title> RSS Integration</title>
		<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Please download RSSLib4J from <a href="http://devzone.stealthp.org/cms/index.php?page=RSSLib4J#RSSLib4J"> here</a>.</p>
		<p><strong>Motivation:</strong> Today there are two fundamental ways to connect to a Web service:</p>
		<ul>
		  <li>Bootstrap the consumer with the service's WSDL file.</li>
		  <li>Use a UDDI registry to look up a service.</li>
		</ul>
		<p>The problem for many small organizations is that UDDI is a substantial investment in terms of licensing, programming to the APIs, and perhaps hosting.
           UDDI seems like a lot of infrastructure for simply looking up a Web service. And if the developer doesn't want to bootstrap using a WSDL file, what other alternative do they have?
			<br/>
			Why not use RSS as a place to syndicate Web services in a simple way. I found <a href="http://www.xml.com/pub/a/2002/12/18/dive-into-xml.html#RSS"> this</a> site useful in describing RSS and its various flavors. RSS stands for Really Simple Syndication and is used by news web sites and bloggers to create feeds. Basically RSS provides a channel that contains one or more items. Each item has, among other things, a title, a description, and a link. Usually the link is an HTML link to the news or blog content. However there is no reason why that link cannot be to a link to a service's WSDL.</p>
		<p><strong>Description:</strong> This demo uses CeltiXfire and an RSS feed parser called RSSLib4J that you can <a href="http://devzone.stealthp.org/cms/index.php?page=RSSLib4J#RSSLib4J"> download here</a>. It includes a simple class that wraps the RSSLib4J APIs in order to use them for a name lookup for a WSDL from the feed.
<br/>
This demo is similar to the simple Hello_World demo. The major differences are the source of the WSDL and how the client looks up the service's WSDL.
The client uses the new RSSSRegistry class to parse the RSS feed. It then uses the link provided through the feed to bootstrap the service's WDL.
The build.xml has been modified to pickup the RSSLib4J jar file in the demo's lib directory.
<br/>
Please read the readme.txt file for more information on running the demo.
</p>
    <p><strong>Contributed by:</strong> <a href="mailto:william.henry@iona.com">William Henry</a></p>
    <p><strong>Created:</strong> 10 January 2006</p>
    <p><strong>Last updated:</strong> 8 Febuary 2006</p>
    <p><strong>Tested with:</strong>Celtix 1.0</p>
    <p><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="./rss/hello_world_RSS.zip">zip</a></p>
  </section>
    <section id="bpel">
	  <title>ActiveBPEL Integration</title>
	  <p><strong>Description:</strong> In many situations, developers need to integrate several Web service applications into a larger application, such as
      using a credit checking service, an inventory service, or a shipping service to process a sales order. It is
      possible to write an application that accepts customer input, invokes the various services, and then returns shipping
      and billing information to the customer. However, an alternative approach would be to define the process using business process execution
      language (BPEL) and leave the details of persistence, compensation, coordination, and exception handling to a business process engine.
      This demo shows how to use the ActiveBPEL business process engine to coordinate information flow between multiple CeltiXfire Web service
      applications. This demo also shows interoperability between CeltiXfire and the ActiveBPEL engine, which uses Axis as its underlying
      Web services toolkit.</p>
	  <p><strong>Contributed by:</strong> John Lifter</p>
	  <p><strong>Created:</strong> 27 January 2006</p>
      <p><strong>Last updated:</strong> 27 January 2006</p>
	  <p><strong>Tested with:</strong> Celtix 1.0</p>
	  <p><strong>Download:</strong></p>
    <ul>
      <li>Overview (<a href="./bepl/celtix_activeBPEL_integration.pdf">pdf</a>)</li>
      <li>Source (<a href="./bepl/celtix_activeBPEL_integration.zip">zip</a>)</li>
    </ul>
	</section>
	  </section>
  </body>
</document>
