<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
  or more contributor license agreements. See the NOTICE file
  distributed with this work for additional information
  regarding copyright ownership. The ASF licenses this file
  to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
  "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
  with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
 
  http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
 
  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  KIND, either express or implied. See the License for the
  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  under the License.
-->
<!--
  Copyright 2002-2004 The Apache Software Foundation or its licensors,
  as applicable.

  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at

      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE faqs PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD FAQ V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/faq-v20.dtd">

<faqs>
  <title>General FAQ</title>

  <faqsection id="basic">
    <title>Basics</title>
    <faq>
      <question>
        What is CeltiXfire?
      </question>
      <answer>
    Cetlix is an open source Java Web services ESB implementation. It is based on JAX-WS 2.0.
      </answer>
    </faq>
	<faq>
	<question>
	What is an ESB?
	</question>
	<answer>
	ESB stands for Enterprise Service Bus. An ESB is the layer of technology that makes SOA possible. 
	It enables the abstraction by translating the messages defining the services into data that can 
	be manipulated by a physical process implementing a service. Essentially, an ESB is the yarn 
	that weaves a SOA together.
	</answer>
	</faq>
	<faq>
	<question>
	What is SOA?
	</question>
	<answer>
	SOA stands for Service-Oriented Architecture. Service-Oriented Architecture is an approach 
	to software architecture with the goal to decouple the agents of work in a software system 
	from the functionality advertised by those agents.  An agent offers a contract, representing 
	a service, which can then be consumed by other software agents that require work to be done. 
	In SOA terms, the contract-offering agent is the Service Provider, and the contract itself 
	represents the Service. Using SOA, system designers can describe the core functions of the 
	system as service elements that can be composed and reused to form business applications.
	</answer>
	</faq>
	</faqsection>
	<faqsection id="esbrelates">
	<title>Relationship to Other ESBs</title>
	<faq>
	<question>
	How does CeltiXfire compare to other open source ESBs like Mule and ServiceMix?
	</question>
	<answer>
	CeltiXfire is the only ESB that implements the JAX-WS specification. Also, CeltiXfire has the ability 
	to send SOAP messages over HTTP built-in, and it does not require any external program for 
	this functionality, like Apache Axis. Also, CeltiXfire is not based on a particular messaging 
	technology. It supports JMS and comes with ActiveMQ, but it can work with any JMS implementation. 
	CeltiXfire is extensible, so it is possible to write other messaging transports for CeltiXfire since
	the messaging bus is not tightly bound to how CeltiXfire works.
	</answer>
	</faq>
	<faq>
	<question>
	How does CeltiXfire compare to commercial ESBs?
	</question>
	<answer>
	Due to the rapid innovation capability of an open source community, CeltiXfire is comparable, 
	and ahead in some ways, in capability to commercial Java-centric ESBs. For example, CeltiXfire is 
	currently the only ESB with JAX-WS support. The non-Java-centric ESBs complement and interoperate 
	with CeltiXfire to provide additional transports and bindings, i.e. IONA's Artix product provides 
	additional capabilities to integrate with IBM MQ, CORBA, Tuxedo, etc.
	</answer>
	</faq>
	</faqsection>
	<faqsection id="osrelates">
	<title>Relationship to Other Open Source Projects</title>
	<faq>
	<question>
	Does CeltiXfire use other open source projects?
	</question>
	<answer>
	<p>Yes. CeltiXfire is built and packaged using Maven 2.0 from Apache. The Web site is built using Forrest 
	from Apache. All of the documentation for the CeltiXfire project is written using OpenOffice 2.0.</p>
    <p>The CeltiXfire team is also working with the STP project at the Eclipse foundation to build a set of GUI tools for developing SOAs.</p>
	</answer>
	</faq>
	<faq>
	<question>
	What other open source projects does CeltiXfire work with?
	</question>
	<answer>
	Currently a number of open source projects are in discussions with the CeltiXfire project about taking shared dependencies.
	</answer>
	</faq>
	<faq>
	<question>
	Are members of the CeltiXfire community working with any open-source JBI projects?
	</question>
	<answer>
	Yes.
	</answer>
	</faq>
	<faq>
	<question>
	Are members of the CeltiXfire community working with any open-source SCA projects?
	</question>
	<answer>
	Yes.
	</answer>
	</faq>
	</faqsection>
</faqs>
