<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<chapter>
  <title>Admonitions</title>
  <section>
    <title>Overview</title>
    <para>Admonitions are pieces of text that are offset from the main flow of text. They include 
	      things like warnings, notes, and tips. They should be used sparingly because they 
		  interupt the flow of the text. However, if you think one is needed, use one.</para>
	<para>As a general rule, warnings and notes are the <emphasis role="strong">prefered</emphasis> 
	      admonitions in CeltiXire documentation. That does not mean the use of the other types are 
		  prohibited. It only means that they should be used with caution.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="warn">
    <title>Warnings</title>
	<para>Warnings are used to callout instances where a serious loss of data could occur. The 
	      text of the warning should make it clear what will cause the data loss and what data 
		  is at risk. For example, if using a value greater than 1 million will cause a method 
		  invocation to return garbage, you should use a warning to mention this.</para>
	<para>Warnings are marked up using a <sgmltag class="element">warning</sgmltag> element. The 
	      <sgmltag class="element">warning</sgmltag> element should contain a single 
		  <sgmltag class="element">para</sgmltag> element that contains the text for the warning.</para>
	<para>The <sgmltag class="element">warning</sgmltag> element can, however, contain more than one 
	      paragraph, a code listing, or a table. These are exceptions that are to be used sparingly.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="note">
    <title>Notes</title>
	<para>Notes are used to callout information that the reader should be aware of, but is 
	      ancillary to the topic being discused in the main flow of the text. For example, if you 
		  are discussing the mapping of a CORBA service from IDL to WSDL and want to reference the
		  official IDL to WSDL mapping, you might put the reference in a note.</para>
	<para>Notes are marked up using a <sgmltag class="element">note</sgmltag> element. Like the 
	      <sgmltag class="element">warning</sgmltag> element, the <sgmltag class="element">note</sgmltag> 
		  element should contain a single <sgmltag class="element">para</sgmltag> element that 
		  contains the text for the warning. The <sgmltag class="element">note</sgmltag> element 
		  can also contain more than one paragraph, a code listing, or a table.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Footnotes</title>
	<para>In general, you should not need to use footnotes in CeltiXfire documentation. If you 
	      find that a footnote is required, you can use one. However, most information that would 
		  be put in a footnote is more appropriately placed in a note. For example, if there is a 
		  related specification for a feature or some other ancilary piece of information, you might 
		  put it in a footnote.</para>
	<para>Footnotes are marked up using the <sgmltag class="element">footnote</sgmltag> element. 
	      The <sgmltag class="element">footnote</sgmltag> element must contain a block element such 
		  as a <sgmltag class="element">para</sgmltag> element or a 
		  <sgmltag class="element">table</sgmltag> element. The contents of the footnote will be 
		  placed according to the formatting rules and a link will be inserted where the 
		  <sgmltag class="element">footnote</sgmltag> element was in the text.</para>
	<para>In addition to using a footnote as a holder for text, you can also create a footnot that 
		  refers to another footnote. To do this you use the 
		  <sgmltag class="element">footnoteref</sgmltag> element. It takes a single attribute, 
		  <sgmltag class="attribute">linkend</sgmltag>, that specifies the 
		  <sgmltag class="attribute">id</sgmltag> of the referenced footnote. The generated link 
		  will point back to the referenced footnote.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Others</title>
    <para>In addition to the above admonition types, Docbook has elements for three other types:</para>
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem><para><link linkend="caution">cautions</link></para></listitem>
	  <listitem><para><link linkend="important">important notes</link></para></listitem>
	  <listitem><para><link linkend="tip">tips</link></para></listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<section id="caution">
	  <title>Cautions</title>
	  <para>Cautions are intended for use when a <link linkend="warn">warning</link> is too 
	        strong. For example, a caution may be used when an action will potentially cuase a 
			service to return an exception, but not crash or result in any loss of critical data. 
			In general, it is best to use a <link linkend="warn">warning</link>.</para>
		<para>Cautions are marked up using the <sgmltag class="element">caution</sgmltag> element.
		      As with warnings elements, the <sgmltag class="element">caution</sgmltag> element 
			  should contain only a single <sgmltag class="element">para</sgmltag> element.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="important">
	  <title>Important Notes</title>
	  <para>Important notes are used to point out information that is important for the user to 
	        know, but that may not be obvious. For example, if you change a value in a context and 
			the new value overrides a transport setting for the service. Or if the new value 
			persists for all future uses of the context.</para>
	  <para>Important notes are marked up using the <sgmltag class="element">important</sgmltag> 
	        element. The <sgmltag class="element">important</sgmltag> element should contain 
			only a single <sgmltag class="element">para</sgmltag> element. However, it is 
			allowable to use other block elements in an important note.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="tip">
	  <title>Tips</title>
	  <para>Tips are bits of information that may help a user be more productive, but that are not 
	        critical to using the product. In general, this type of information should either be 
			worked directly into the text or placed in a <link linkend="note">note</link>.</para>
	  <para>Tips are marked up using the <sgmltag class="element">tip</sgmltag> element. The 
	        <sgmltag class="element">tip</sgmltag> element should contain only a single 
		    <sgmltag class="element">para</sgmltag> element. However, it is allowable to use other 
		    block elements in a tip.</para>
	</section>
  </section>
</chapter>