<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<chapter>
  <title>Admonitions</title>
  <section>
    <title>Overview</title>
    <para>Admonitions are pieces of text that are offset from the main flow of text. They include 
	      things like warnings, notes, and tips. They should be used sparingly because they 
		  interupt the flow of the text. However, if you think one is needed, use one.</para>
	<para>As a general rule, warnings and notes are the <emphasis role="strong">prefered</emphasis> 
	      admonitions in CFX documentation. That does not mean the use of the other types are 
		  prohibited. It only means that they should be used with caution.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Warnings</title>
	<para>Warnings are used to callout instances where a serious loss of data could occur. The 
	      text of the warning should make it clear what will cause the data loss and what data 
		  is at risk. For example, if using a value greater than 1 million will cause a method 
		  invocation to return garbage, you should use a warning to mention this.</para>
	<para>Warnings are marked up using a <sgmltag class="element">warning</sgmltag> element. The 
	      <sgmltag class="element">warning</sgmltag> element should contain a single 
		  <sgmltag class="element">para</sgmltag> element that contains the text for the warning.</para>
	<para>The <sgmltag class="element">warning</sgmltag> element can, however, contain more than one 
	      paragraph, a code listing, or a table. These are exceptions that are to be used sparingly.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Notes</title>
	<para>Notes are used to callout information that the reader should be aware of, but is 
	      ancillary to the topic being discused in the main flow of the text. For example, if you 
		  are discussing the mapping of a CORBA service from IDL to WSDL and want to reference the
		  official IDL to WSDL mapping, you might put the reference in a note.</para>
	<para>Notes are marked up using a <sgmltag class="element">note</sgmltag> element. Like the 
	      <sgmltag class="element">warning</sgmltag> element, the <sgmltag class="element">note</sgmltag> 
		  element should contain a single <sgmltag class="element">para</sgmltag> element that 
		  contains the text for the warning. The <sgmltag class="element">note</sgmltag> element 
		  can also contain more than one paragraph, a code listing, or a table.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Footnotes</title>
	<para>In general, you should not need to use footnotes in CeltiXfire documentation. If you 
	      find that a footnote is required, you can use one. However, most information that would 
		  be put in a footnote is more appropriately placed in a note. For example, if there is a 
		  related specification for a feature or some other ancilary piece of information, you might 
		  put it in a footnote.</para>
	<para>Footnotes are marked up using the <sgmltag class="element">footnote</sgmltag> element. 
	      </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Others</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
</chapter>
