<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<chapter>
  <title>Cross References and Links</title>
  <section>
    <title>Overview</title>
	<para>The CeliXfire documentation uses a subset of the linking elements defined by Docbook. The 
	      elements include:</para>
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para><link linkend="xref"><sgmltag class="element">xref</sgmltag></link></para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para><link linkend="link"><sgmltag class="element">link</sgmltag></link></para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para><link linkend="ulink"><sgmltag class="element">ulink</sgmltag></link></para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem><para><sgmltag class="element">anchor</sgmltag></para></listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>Using this set of elements, you can create cross references, internal links, and external 
	      links in your documents.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Internal Links and Cross References</title>
	<para>Internal links are links whose anchor is in the same document. A cross reference is a 
	      special instance of an internal link. Where an internal link requires that you supply the 
		  text that is displayed, as with an HTML link, a cross reference's text is automatically 
		  determined by the link's target.</para>
	<section id="link">
	  <title>Inserting an Internal Link</title>
	  <para>Internal links are created using the <sgmltag class="element">link</sgmltag> element. 
	        The <sgmltag class="element">link</sgmltag> element has one required attribute 
			<sgmltag class="attribute">linkend</sgmltag> whose value is the id of element 
			anchoring the link. The anchoring element can be any valid Docbook element that uses 
			the <sgmltag class="attribute">id</sgmltag> attribute. For example if you wanted to 
			create a link to an image in your document, you could use the id of the 
			<sgmltag class="element">figure</sgmltag> element that wraps the image.</para>
	  <note>
	    <para>You can also create anchor points in your text using the 
		      <sgmltag class="element">anchor</sgmltag> element. In this case, the value of the 
			  <sgmltag class="attribute">linkend</sgmltag> attribute would be the id of the 
			  <sgmltag class="element">anchor</sgmltag> element.</para>
	  </note>
	  <para>The text used for the link is the content of the 
	        <sgmltag class="element">link</sgmltag> element. <xref linkend="linkexample" /> shows 
			the mark up for this <link linkend="link">link to the top</link> of this section.</para>
	  <example id="linkexample">
	    <title>Example of an Internal Link</title>
		<programlisting>this &lt;link linkend="link"&gt;link to the top&lt;/link&gt; of</programlisting>
	  </example>
	</section>
	<section id="xref">
	  <title>Inserting a Cross Reference</title>
	  <para>Cross references are created using the <sgmltag class="element">xref</sgmltag> element. 
	        Like the <sgmltag class="element">link</sgmltag> element, the 
			<sgmltag class="element">xref</sgmltag> element requires the use of the 
			<sgmltag class="attribute">linkend</sgmltag> attribute to identify the element being 
			referenced.</para>
	  <para>Unlike the <sgmltag class="element">link</sgmltag> element, the 
	        <sgmltag class="element">xref</sgmltag> element does not have any contents. The text 
			displayed for the generated link is generated based on the contents of the referenced 
			element. If the referenced element has a <sgmltag class="element">title</sgmltag> 
			element, such as a <sgmltag class="element">section</sgmltag> element or a 
			<sgmltag class="element">example</sgmltag> element, the contents of the 
			<sgmltag class="element">title</sgmltag> element is used as the link text. 
			Alternatively, the value of the referenced element's 
			<sgmltag class="attribute">xreflable</sgmltag> attribute will be used as the link 
			text.</para>
	  <note>
	    <para>If the referenced element has both a <sgmltag class="element">title</sgmltag> 
		      element and a value specified in its <sgmltag class="attribute">xreflable</sgmltag> 
			  attribute, the value of the <sgmltag class="attribute">xreflable</sgmltag> attribute 
			  is used.</para>
	  </note>
	  <para><xref linkend="xrefexample1" /> shows an example of a cross reference whose text is 
	        derived from the <sgmltag class="element">title</sgmltag> element of the referenced 
			element. The resulting link text would be <literal>the section called "Coco Crisps" 
			shows</literal>.</para>
	  <example id="xrefexample1">
	    <title>Cross Reference to a Titled Element</title>
		<programlisting>&lt;para&gt;&lt;xref linkend="topsect" /&gt; shows ...&lt;/para&gt;
...
&lt;section id="topsect"&gt;
  &lt;title&gt;Coco Crisps&lt;/title&gt;
...
&lt;/section&gt;</programlisting>
	  </example>
	  <para><xref linkend="xrefexample2" /> shows an example of a cross reference whose text is 
	        derived from the <sgmltag class="attribute">xreflable</sgmltag> attribute of the 
			referenced element. The resulting link text would be <literal>short stop shows</literal>
			.</para>
	  <example id="xrefexample2">
	    <title>Cross Reference to an Element with an Xreflable</title>
		<programlisting>&lt;para&gt;&lt;xref linkend="example1" /&gt; shows ...&lt;/para&gt;
...
&lt;example id="example1" xlableref="short stop"&gt;
  &lt;title&gt;Catching Coco Crisp&lt;/title&gt;
  ...
&lt;/example&gt;</programlisting>
	  </example>
	</section>
  </section>
  <section id="ulink">
    <title>External Links</title>
	<para>External links are links to resources that are not contianed in the same XML source 
	      document. They do not have to be links to other documents. They can be links to Web pages 
		  or any other resource that can be reached using a URL. Generally, they are transformed 
		  into HTML links when the document is published.</para>
	<para>External links are created using the <sgmltag class="element">ulink</sgmltag> element. 
	      You identify the linked resource using the required <sgmltag class="attribute">url</sgmltag> 
		  attribute. The value must be a valid URL.</para>
    <note>
	  <para>Because the CeltiXfire documentation is built with Forrest, you can use the 
	        <filename>site:<replaceable>siteId</replaceable></filename> resource identifier to 
			refer to pages that are listed in <filename>site.xml</filename>.</para>
	</note>
	<para>The link text can be specified in one of two ways. You can specified the desired link 
	      text as the value of the <sgmltag class="element">ulink</sgmltag> element. If you leave 
		  the <sgmltag class="element">ulink</sgmltag> element empty, the value of the 
		  <sgmltag class="attribute">url</sgmltag> attribute will be used as the link text.</para>
	<para><xref linkend="ulinkexample1"/> shows an example of an external link with supplied link 
	      text.</para>
	<example id="ulinkexample1">
	  <title>External Link with Link Text</title>
	  <programlisting>&lt;ulink url="http://celtixfire.org"&gt;CeltiXfire Home&lt;/ulink&gt;</programlisting>
	</example>
	<para><xref linkend="ulinkexample2"/> shows an example of an external link that uses the default 
	      link text.</para>
	<example id="ulinkexample2">
	  <title>External Link Using Default Link Text</title>
	  <programlisting>&lt;ulink url="http://celtixfire.org" /&gt;</programlisting>
	</example>
  </section>
</chapter>