<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="overview">
  <title>Writing Documentation for CeltiXfire (CXF)</title>

  <section>
    <title>Why XML Based Documents?</title>

    <para>The easy answer is because XML is cool!! However, it does have some
    distinct advantages over other means of sourcing documentation:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>It is stored as text files.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>It provides structure to a document.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>It is an easy way to single source documentation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <simplesect>
      <title>Text vs. Binary</title>

      <para>Text files have a number of advantages over binary formats:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>They tend to take up less space.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>They can be edited by a slew of freely available tools.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>They can be easily diffed when being committed to a
          repository.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>They are readable by both humans and machines.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </simplesect>

    <simplesect>
      <title>Structure</title>

      <para>Writing documentation with a markup language may give writers
      visions of troff and LaTex. Unlike those markups, the XML tags used by
      both XDOC and DocBook are used to describe the structure of a document.
      It also provides tags to help identify different types of content with
      in your document.</para>

      <para>This means that it It makes no assumptions about the presentation
      of the content. Using a structured markup allows you to worry about
      creating and structuring your content.</para>
    </simplesect>

    <simplesect>
      <title>Single Source, Multiple Outputs</title>

      <para>Formatting is handled by back end processing tools. CeltiXfire
      (CXF) uses Apache Forrest to generate HTML and PDF versions of its
      content. There are also a number of other tools, both open source and
      commercial, that generate documentation from XML source. This means that
      all of the writers can work on a consistent framework no matter what the
      eventual output medium is going to be.</para>

      <para>Using these tools, you can completely customize the look of your
      documentation without needing to change the documentation source. If at
      some point in the future you decide to update the look and feel of your
      documentation, you simply update the stylesheets used to process the
      XML. The source content never needs to change.</para>
    </simplesect>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>General Guidelines</title>

    <simplesect>
      <title>Types of XML Used</title>

      <para>Depending on the type of document you are writing you will use one
      of two types of XML:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="#FAQ">FAQs in XDOC</ulink></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="#the_rest">Everything else in
          DocBook</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </simplesect>

    <simplesect>
      <title>Formatting the XML</title>

      <para>To make the source as readable as possible there are a few general
      guidelines to follow when writing CXF documentation:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Keep lines under 100 characters long so that they can be read
          easily.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Don't leave white space between elements.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Use indenting to show the hierarchy.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </simplesect>
  </section>

  <section id="FAQ">
    <title>Writing FAQs</title>

    <para>FAQs are written using Apache's xdoc format. This format was chosen
    for its simplicity. You can find more information on the xdoc format used
    for FAQs <ulink
    url="http://forrest.apache.org/dtdx/faq-v20.dtdx.html">here</ulink>.</para>

    <para>Depending on the complexity of the FAQ topic, you can include FAQ
    sections inside of an FAQ document. Typically, however, an FAQ should have
    fewer than 20 questions.</para>

    <para>When naming an FAQ you need to append <filename>-faq</filename> to
    the name of the file. For example, an FAQ about the CXF JAX-WS
    implementation could be called <filename>jaxws-faq.xml</filename>.</para>
  </section>

  <section id="the_rest">
    <title>Writing General Documentation</title>

    <para>All other types of documentation are written using DocBook 4.2.
    DocBook 4.2 provides a structured, XML based grammar for writing complex
    technical documentation. It is also an OASIS standard. This makes it a
    natural fit for writing open source documentation.</para>

    <para>The remainder of this style guide discusses how the CXF project uses
    DocBook. For more general references and some help getting familiar with
    DocBook, see the following:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://DocBook.org/">DocBook.org</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
        url="http://opensource.bureau-cornavin.com/crash-course/">The Crash
        Course to DocBook</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://nwalsh.com/DocBook/">Norman Walsh's DocBook
        page</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>