<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <title>Code Listings and Other Code Snippets</title>

  <section>
    <title>Overview</title>

    <para>There are several instances when you will need to code in the
    CeltiXfire documentation. You may need to use a class name, interface
    name, or element name as part of a sentence. You will also need to provide
    long code samples in many places. Docbook has a number of elements that
    are used for placing code in your documentation. </para>

    <note>
      <para>XML mark-up, such as WSDL and XMLSchema, are also considered code
      for the purposes of CeltiXfire documentation.</para>
    </note>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Code Listings</title>

    <section>
      <title>Examples</title>

      <para>When providing code examples, you need to seperate them from the
      text and provide a caption for them. To do this you use the <sgmltag
      class="element">example</sgmltag> element. You should always provide a
      descriptive value for the <sgmltag class="element">example</sgmltag>
      element's <sgmltag class="attribute">id</sgmltag> attribute.</para>

      <para>As shown in <xref linkend="example_example" />, the first child of
      the example element is a title element. The contents of the title
      element will be used as the caption of the example. It will also be used
      as the text for any cross references.</para>

      <note>
        <para>If you want to have different text appear when cross referencing
        an example, set the <sgmltag class="element">example</sgmltag>
        element's <sgmltag class="attribute">xreflabel</sgmltag>
        attribute.</para>
      </note>

      <para>The last child of the example element is the <sgmltag
      class="element">programlisting</sgmltag> element. The <sgmltag
      class="element">programlisting</sgmltag> element contains the code
      sample itself. Any text placed inside the programlisting element is
      treated literally. Therefore, any spacing that you use will be exactly
      reproduced when the document is produced.</para>

      <warning>
        <para>When using XML inside a <sgmltag>programlisting</sgmltag>
        element you must not use the <code>&lt;</code> or <code>&gt;</code>
        characters. Instead use <wordasword>&amp;lt;</wordasword> and
        <wordasword>&amp;gt;</wordasword>.</para>
      </warning>

      <example id="example_example">
        <title>Example Mark-Up</title>

        <programlisting></programlisting>
      </example>

      <section>
        <title>Using Callouts</title>

        <para>I need to figure out how to write the mark-up for using
        callouts. It is complicated and I haven't had time to really try
        it.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Code Blocks</title>

      <para>These are short code listings that are not in-lined.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>In-Line Code</title>

    <para></para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Class Synopses</title>

    <para></para>
  </section>
</chapter>