<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<chapter>
  <title>Working with Code</title>
  <section>
    <title>Overview</title>
    <para>There are several instances when you will need to code in the
    CeltiXfire documentation. You may need to use a class name, interface
    name, or element name as part of a sentence. You will also need to provide
    long code samples in many places. Docbook has a number of elements that
    are used for placing code in your documentation. </para>
    <note>
      <para>XML mark-up, such as WSDL and XMLSchema, are also considered code
      for the purposes of CeltiXfire documentation.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Code Listings</title>
    <section>
      <title>Examples</title>
      <para>When providing code examples, you need to seperate them from the
      text and provide a caption for them. To do this you use the <sgmltag class="element">example</sgmltag> element. You should always provide a
      descriptive value for the <sgmltag class="element">example</sgmltag>
      element&apos;s <sgmltag class="attribute">id</sgmltag> attribute.</para>
      <para>As shown in <xref linkend="example_example"/>, the first child of
      the example element is a title element. The contents of the title
      element will be used as the caption of the example. It will also be used
      as the text for any cross references.</para>
      <note>
        <para>If you want to have different text appear when cross referencing
        an example, set the <sgmltag class="element">example</sgmltag>
        element&apos;s <sgmltag class="attribute">xreflabel</sgmltag>
        attribute.</para>
      </note>
      <para>The last child of the example element is the <sgmltag class="element">programlisting</sgmltag> element. The <sgmltag class="element">programlisting</sgmltag> element contains the code
      sample itself. Any text placed inside the programlisting element is
      treated literally. Therefore, any spacing that you use will be exactly
      reproduced when the document is produced.</para>
      <warning>
        <para>When using XML inside a <sgmltag class="element">programlisting</sgmltag>
        element you must not use the   <literal>&lt;</literal> or  
        <literal>&gt;</literal>characters. Instead use <wordasword>&amp;lt;</wordasword> and
        <wordasword>&amp;gt;</wordasword>.</para>
      </warning>
      <example id="example_example">
        <title>Example Mark-Up</title>
        <programlisting>&lt;example id=&quot;example_example&quot;&gt;
  &lt;title&gt;Example Mark-Up&lt;/title&gt;
  &lt;programlisting&gt;public class ServiceName extends javax.xml.ws.Service
{
  ...
  public ServiceName(URL wsdlLocation, QName serviceName) { }
  
  public ServiceName() { }

  public Greeter getPortName() { }
  .
  .
  .
}</programlisting>
      </example>
      <section>
        <title>Using Callouts</title>
        <para>I need to figure out how to write the mark-up for using
        callouts. It is complicated and I haven&apos;t had time to really try
        it.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Code Blocks</title>
      <para>There are cases when you need to use a block of code, but do not need to create a formal example with a title. In such cases you can use one of two methods:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use an <sgmltag class="element">informalexample</sgmltag> element</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use a <sgmltag class="element">programlisting</sgmltag> element</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>In terms of the generated output, there is no difference between the two approaches. The real difference is in the complexity of the mark-up and the formality of the structure you wish to use. In the CeltiXfire documentation, the prefered method is to simply use the <sgmltag class="element">programlisting</sgmltag> element. However, if you feel that a code block needs to be wrapped in an <sgmltag class="element">informalexample</sgmltag> element, that is fine.</para>
      <para><xref linkend="block_example"/> shows the mark-up for a standalone block of code.</para>
      <example id="block_example">
        <title>Example Code Block</title>
        <programlisting>&lt;programlisting&gt;var WebServiceProvider1 = {
    &apos;wsdlLocation&apos;: &apos;file:./wsdl/hello_world.wsdl&apos;,
    &apos;serviceName&apos;: &apos;SOAPService1&apos;,
    &apos;portName&apos;: &apos;SoapPort1&apos;,
    &apos;targetNamespace&apos;: http://objectweb.org/hello_world_soap_http&apos;,
};&lt;/programlisting&gt;</programlisting>
      </example>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>In-line Code</title>
    <para>There are many instances where you need to place a code artifact in a block of text such as when you are refering to a Java class or an XML element. Docbook has a number of specialized elements for placing code artifacts in-line. The ones used in CeltiXfire include:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><sgmltag class="element">sgmltag</sgmltag></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><sgmltag>classname</sgmltag></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><sgmltag>interfacename</sgmltag></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><sgmltag>methodname</sgmltag></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <section>
      <title>XML Artifacts</title>
      <para>When placing XML artifacts such as element names or attribute names in your text wrap them in an <sgmltag class="element">sgmltag</sgmltag> element. To specify the type of XML artifact, the <sgmltag class="element">sgmltag</sgmltag> element&apos;s <sgmltag class="attribute">class</sgmltag> attribute is always used. <xref linkend="class_values"/> shows the values used for the <sgmltag class="attribute">class</sgmltag> attribute.</para>
      <table id="class_values">
        <title>Values for the <sgmltag class="attribute">class</sgmltag> Atribute</title>
        <tgroup cols="2">
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry>Value</entry>
              <entry>Description</entry>
            </row>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <sgmltag class="attvalue">attribute</sgmltag>
              </entry>
              <entry>Specifies that the artifact is an attribute of an XML element.</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <sgmltag class="attvalue">element</sgmltag>
              </entry>
              <entry>Specifies that the artifact is an XML element.</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <sgmltag class="attvalue">attrvalue</sgmltag>
              </entry>
              <entry>Specifies that the artifact is the value of an XML element&apos;s attribute.</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <sgmltag class="attvalue">emptytag</sgmltag>
              </entry>
              <entry>Specifies an XML element that does not hold any data such as <sgmltag class="emptytag">foo</sgmltag>.</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>General Programming Language Artifacts</title>
      <para>This is for things like function and other stuff.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Object Oriented Programming Language Artifacts</title>
      <para>This is all of the programing things like interface name and classname.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Class Synopses</title>
    <para>This is pretty complex stuff. It needs to cover both class and ooclass.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
